Ra'Fat A. AL-Msie'Deen

Curriculum Vitae



R.O. Box 61710, Mu'tah University, Alkarak - Jordan

0096279542341

✓ rafatals3ode@gmail.com

https://rafat66.github.io/Al-Msie-Deen/

in Linkedin

RafatALs3ode

PERSONAL DETAILS

Full Name Ra'fat Ahmad Ali AL–Msie'Deen

Place O.B Tafila – Jordan Nationality Jordanian

RESUME

My name is Ra'Fat Al-Msie'Deen and I am an Associate Professor at the faculty of information technology in the department of software engineering at the Mutah University, Al Karak – Jordan. I received my PhD in software engineering from the University of Montpellier 2, Montpellier – France, in 2014. I received my Master's degree in Information Technology from University Utara Malaysia, Kedah – Malaysia, in 2009. I got my B.Sc. in Computer Science from Al-Hussein Bin Talal University, Ma'an – Jordan, in 2007. I have several publications in international journals, conferences and books. I taught several courses in computer science and supervised several B.Sc. students.

PHD DISSERTATION

Reverse Engineering Feature Models From Software Variants to Build Software Product Lines: RIVEPLINE Approach. (University of Montpellier, Montpellier - France)

MASTER THESIS

A Requirement Model of Local News WEB/ WAP Application for Rural Communities. (University Utara Malaysia, Kedah — Malaysia)

SCHOLARSHIPS

A scholarship by the JOSYLEEN PROJECT - ERASMUS MUNDUS ACTION 2 towards PhD in computer science during the period of 2012 - 2014, Montpellier - France

ACADEMIC REFEREE

Marianne HUCHARD Universitè de Montpellier @ Montpellier - France.
Wan OSMAN Universiti Utara Malaysia @ Kedah - Malaysia.
Christelle URTADO LGI2P/Ecole des Mines d'Alès @ Nîmes - France.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science

June, 2014

University of Montpellier, Montpellier - France

Specialization: Software Engineering

TOPICS: Software Engineering and Software Product Line Engineering

Master of Science – Information Technology

March, 2009

University Utara Malaysia, Kedah – Malaysia

GPA: 3.85/4

TOPICS: Systems Analysis and Design, Database, Mobile Programming, Java Language, ...

Bachelor of Computer Science

September, 2007

Al-Hussein Bin Talal University, Ma'an – Jordan

GPA: 72.94%

The General Secondary Education Certificate

August, 2004

Grandel Secondary School, Tafila - Jordan

Scientific Stream GPA: 76.9%

MANAGERIAL EXPERIENCE

Chairman of the Department of CS

September, 2020 - September, 2021

Chairman of the Department of Computer science @ Faculty of Information Technology, Mutah University.

ACADEMIC AND TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Associate Professor

September, 2019 - present

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

Taught Courses: Bachelor and Master Levels

 $\underline{\textbf{Bachelor level}} : \textbf{Requirements Engineering, Software Documentation, Software Architecture and Design, and$

Graduation Project.

Master Level: Advanced Software Engineering.

Assistant Professor

September, 2014 - September, 2019

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

Software Engineering, Computer Organization and Design, Introduction to Information Technology, Operating Systems, Database Systems, Decision Support Systems, E-Commerce Programming, Internet Programming, Special Topics In Computer Science, Computer Skills (I), Communication Skills, Computer skills (II) - Visual Basic, Algorithms, Systems Analysis and Design, Theory of Computation, Logic Circuits Design, and Graduation Project.

Full-Time Lecturer

March, 2009 – December, 2011

Tafila Technical University, Tafila – Jordan

Computer Graphics, Logic Circuits Design, Computer Skills (1), Computer Skills (2), International Computer Driving License "ICDL", Java Language, C++ Language, Database, Information Retrieval Systems, Management Information Systems, Internet Programming, Systems Analysis and Design, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, and Graduation project.

Part-Time Lecturer

September, 2010 – June, 2011

The University of Jordan - Arabian Education and Training Group, Amman - Jordan

Program Name: "High Diploma in Information and Communication Technologies in Education ICTE"

Taught Courses:

Web Design, Graphical Design, and Graduation project.

Member of the MaREL team

January, 2012 – April, 2014

Models and Reuse Engineering Languages Team

MaREL @ Lirmm - Universitè de Montpellier, Montpellier - France

Committee Member July 1-5, 2013

Member of the organization committee for the ECOOP, ECSA and ECMFA conferences

Teacher of Computer Science

October, 2007 – February, 2008

Ministry of Education, Tafila - Jordan

I have taught computer science in primary and secondary schools

Three conferences have been organized in Montpellier - France

SKILLS

Languages Arabic (mother tongue)

English (reading, writing and conversation)

SOFTWARE MATLAB, LATEX, DIRECTOR, DREAM WEAVER, PHOTOSHOP

CERTIFICATES International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL: UN07097892)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Java, Python, C++, HTML, Java Script, Oracle, ASP.NET, PHP

Modeling UML

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research is primarily concerned with software engineering. In particular, my interests include:

- **1** Software Product Line Engineering (SPLE).
- Formal Concept Analysis (FCA).
- **3** Software Documentation.
- Software Visualization.
- **6** Software Comprehension.

PUBLICATIONS

Journal:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Tag Clouds for Software Documents Visualization," *International Journal on Informatics Visualization*, vol. 3, no. 4, pp. 361–364, 2019.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Tag Clouds for Object-Oriented Source Code Visualization," Engineering, Technology & Applied Science Research, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 4243–4248, 2019.
- [3] Mohammed Alsuwaiket, A. Blasi, and R. Al-Msie'deen, "Formulating Module Assessment for Improved Academic Performance Predictability in Higher Education," *Engineering*, *Technology* & *Applied Science Research*, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 4287–4291, 2019.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "Supporting software documentation with source code summarization," *International Journal of Advanced and Applied Sciences*, vol. 6, no. 1, pp. 59–67, 2019.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "The Impact of the Object-Oriented Software Evolution on Software Metrics: The Iris Approach," *Indian Journal of Science and Technology*, vol. 11, no. 8, pp. 1–8, 2018.
- [6] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Automatic labeling of the object-oriented source code: The Lotus approach," Science International-Lahore, vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 45–48, 2018.
- [7] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Visualizing object-oriented software for understanding and documentation," *International Journal of Computer Science and Information Security*, vol. 13, no. 5, pp. 18–27, 2015.
- [8] <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, M. Huchard, A. Seriai, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Automatic documentation of [mined] feature implementations from source code elements and use-case diagrams with the REVPLINE approach," *International Journal of Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering*, vol. 24, no. 10, pp. 1413–1438, 2014.
- [9] A. M. Frijat and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u> "A requirement model of local news wap/web application for rural community," *Advances in Computer Science and Engineering*, vol. 4, no. 1, pp. 37–53, 2010.

Book:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, Object-oriented Software Documentation. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2019.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, and M. Huchard, Reengineering Software Product Variants Into Software Product Line: REVPLINE Approach. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, A Requirement Model of Local News Application for Rural Communities: A New Model for Rural News. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, and C. Urtado, Reverse Engineering Feature Models. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [5] <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, Feature Location in a Collection of Software Product Variants. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.

International Conference:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. Seriai, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Reverse engineering feature models from software configurations using formal concept analysis," in *Proceedings of the Eleventh International Conference on Concept Lattices and Their Applications, Košice, Slovakia, October 7-10, 2014.*, ser. CEUR Workshop Proceedings, K. Bertet and S. Rudolph, Eds., vol. 1252. CEUR-WS.org, 2014, pp. 95–106.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Documenting the mined feature implementations from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software product variants," in *The 26th International Conference on Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering, Hyatt Regency, Vancouver, BC, Canada, July 1-3, 2013.*, M. Reformat, Ed. Knowledge Systems Institute Graduate School, 2014, pp. 138–143.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Feature location in a collection of software product variants using formal concept analysis," in *Safe and Secure Software Reuse 13th International Conference on Software Reuse, ICSR 2013, Pisa, Italy, June 18-20. Proceedings*, ser. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, J. M. Favaro and M. Morisio, Eds., vol. 7925. Springer, 2013, pp. 302–307.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Mining features from the object-oriented source code of software variants by combining lexical and structural similarity," in *IEEE 14th International Conference on Information Reuse & Integration, IRI 2013, San Francisco, CA, USA, August 14-16, 2013.* IEEE, 2013, pp. 586–593.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Mining features from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software variants using formal concept analysis and latent semantic indexing," in *The 25th International Conference on Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering, Boston, MA, USA, June 27-29, 2013.* Knowledge Systems Institute Graduate School, 2013, pp. 244–249.
- [6] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. D. Seriai, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and A. Al-Khlifat, "Concept lattices: A representation space to structure software variability," in *Information and Communication* Systems (ICICS), 2014 5th International Conference on, Irbid, Jordan, April 2014, pp. 1–6.

International Workshop:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. D. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "An approach to recover feature models from object-oriented source code," in *Actes de la Journée Lignes de Produits* 2012, Lille, France, Novembre 2012, pp. 15–26.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. D. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Feature mining from a collection of software product variants," in *Actes de la Journées GDR GPL CIEL AFADL 2013*, Nancy, France, April 2013, pp. 1–2.
- [3] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and R. Al-Msie'deen, "Recovering traceability links between feature models and source code of product variants," in *Proceedings of the VARiability for You Workshop: Variability Modeling Made Useful for Everyone*, ser. VARY '12. New York, NY, USA: ACM, 2012, pp. 21–25.

- [4] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Identifying traceability links between product variants and their features," in *REVE'2013: 1st International workshop on Reverse Variability Engineering*, 2013, pp. 17–23.
- [5] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and R. Al-Msie'deen, "Genetic algorithms as recovering traceability links method between feature models and source code of product variants," in *Actes de la Journée Lignes de Produits 2012*, Lille, France, Novembre 2012, pp. 3–14.

Poster:

[1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "A methodology to recover feature models from object-oriented source code," Innsbruck, Austria, September 2012.

Doctoral Symposium:

[1] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Mining feature models from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software product variants," in *Doctoral Symposium of ECOOP'13*, Montpellier, France, July 2013, pp. 1–10.